所以我过着孤独的生活。
so i lived my life alone.
没有一个可以真正倾诉的人。
without anyone that i could really talk to.
直到六年前我的飞机在撒哈拉沙漠出了事故。
until i had an accident with my plane in the desert of sahara six years ago.
我的引擎坏了。
something was broken in my engine.
我身边既没有机械师，也没有乘客。
and as i had with me, neither a mechanic nor any passengers.
我决心独自完成这项艰巨的修理工作。
i set myself to attempt the difficult repairs all alone.
这对我来说是生死攸关的问题。我几乎没有足够维持一个星期的饮用水。
it was a question of life or death for me. i had scarcely enough drinking water to last a week.
那么，第一晚。
the first night, then.
我在远离人烟千里之外的沙滩上睡着了。
i went to sleep on the sand a thousand miles from any human habitation.
我比一个在大海中围着木筏漂流的遇难水手还要孤独。
i was more isolated than a shipwrecked sailor around the raft in the middle of the ocean.
因此，你可以想象，当我在日出时被一个点头的小男孩叫醒时，我有多么惊讶。
thus, you can imagine my amazement at sunrise when i was awakened by a nod little boys.
它说如果你给我画一只羊。
it said if you please draw me a sheep.
什么。
what.
给我画一只羊。
draw me a sheep.
我像晴天霹雳一样一下子跳了起来。
i jumped to my feet completely thunderstruck.
我眨眨眼睛，心。我仔细地环顾四周。
i'd blink to my eyes heart. i looked carefully all around me.
我看到一个非常不寻常的小个子站在那里，非常严肃地审视着我。
and i saw a most extraordinary small person who stood there examining me with great seriousness.
在这里你可以看到我后来能画出的最好的他的肖像。
here you may see the best portrait that later i was able to make of him.
但我的画当然没有它的模特迷人。
but my drawing is certainly very much less charming than its model.
然而，这不是我的错。
that, however, is not my fault.
在我六岁的时候，大人们让我在画师生涯中灰心丧气，除了从外面画凉亭和从里面画凉亭之外，我从来没有学过画任何东西。
the grown ups discouraged me in my painters career when i was six years old and i never learnt to draw anything except bowers from the outside and bowers from the inside.
现在，我惊奇地望着这个突然出现的怪物，眼睛都吓得从脑袋里瞪出来了。
now i stared at this sudden apparition with my eyes fairly starting out of my head in astonishment.
记住，我坠落在沙漠里，离任何有人居住的地方都有一千英里远。
remember, i had crashed in the desert a thousand miles from any inhabited region.
然而，我的小家伙似乎既没有在沙漠中迷失方向，也没有因为疲劳、饥饿、口渴或恐惧而昏倒。
and yet my little man seemed neither to be straying uncertainly among the sands nor to be fainting from fatigue or hunger or thirst or fear.
从他身上丝毫看不出他是一个迷失在远离人烟的沙漠中的孩子。
nothing about him gave any suggestion of a child lost in the middle of the desert a thousand miles from any human habitation.
当我终于能说话的时候。我对他说，但是。
when at last i was able to speak. i said to him, but.
你在这里做什么?
what are you doing here.
他非常缓慢地重复着回答。
and in answer he repeated very slowly.
好像他在说一件事关重大的事。
as if he were speaking of a matter of great consequence.
请给我画一只羊。
if you please draw me a sheep.
当一个谜太强大，一个人不敢不服从。
when a mystery is too overpowering, one dare not disobey.
在我看来，这是荒谬的，因为它远离人类的居住地，处于死亡的危险中。
absurd as it might seem to me a thousand miles from any human habitation and in danger of death.
我从口袋里掏出一张纸和一支钢笔。
i took out of my pocket a sheet of paper and my fountain pen.
但这时我想起我的学习重点是地理、历史、算术和语法，我也有点生气地告诉这个小家伙，我不会画画。
but then i remembered how my studies have been concentrated on geography, history, arithmetic and grammar and i tell the little chap a little crossly too that i did not know how to draw.
他回答我。这并不重要。给我画一只羊。
he answered me. that doesn't matter. draw me a sheep.
但我从来没有画过羊。于是我给他画了我经常画的两幅画中的一幅。
but i had never drawn a sheep. so i drew for him one of the two pictures i had drawn so often.
那是一只从外面来的蟒蛇。
it was that of a boa constricter from the outside.
当我听到这个小家伙说不，不，不，我不想在蟒蛇的肚子里放一头大象时，我大吃一惊。
and i was astounded to hear the little fellow greeted with no, no, no, i do not want an elephant inside a boa constrictor.
蟒蛇是一种非常危险的生物，而大象在我住的地方是非常笨重的。所有东西都很小。我需要一只羊，给我画一只羊。
a boa constructor is a very dangerous creature and an elephant is very cumbersome where i live. everything is very small. what i need is a sheep, draw me a sheep.
然后我画了一幅画。
so then i made a drawing.
他仔细地看了看，然后说。
he looked at it carefully, then he said.
不行，这只羊已经病得很重了。让我另一个。
no, this sheep is already very sickly. make me another.
所以我又制造了另一个欢乐。
so i made another joy.
我的朋友温和而宽容地笑了。
my friend smiled gently and indulgently.
你看到你自己。他说这不是一只羊。这是一只公羊，它有角。
you see yourself. he said that this is not a sheep. this is a ram, it has horns.
于是我又重新画了一遍。
so then i did my drawing over once more.
但他也被拒绝了，就像其他人一样。
but he was rejected too, just like the others.
这个太旧了。
this one is too old.
我想要一只活得很长的羊。我的耐心已经耗尽了，因为我急着开始拆引擎。
i want a sheep that will live a long time by this time. my patience was exhausted because i was in a hurry to start taking my engine apart.
我说服了陪审团。
i tossed off this jury.
我给出了一个解释。
and i threw out an explanation with it.
这只是他的箱子，你要的羊就在里面。
this is only his box the sheep you asked for is inside.
我非常惊讶地看到我的年轻法官脸上绽开了一丝光芒。
i was very surprised to see a light break over the face of my young judge.
这正是我想要的。
that is exactly the way i wanted it.
你认为这只羊需要很多草吗?
do you think that this sheep will have to have a great deal of grass.
为什么。
why.
因为在我住的地方，一切都很小。
because where i live, everything is very small.
肯定有足够的草给他吃。我说我给你的是一只很小的羊。
there will surely be enough grass for him. i said it is a very small sheep that i have given you.
他俯下头看那幅画。
he bent his head over the drawing.
没小到你看，他已经睡着了。
not so small that look, he has gone to sleep.
我就这样认识了小王子。
and that is how i made the acquaintance of the little prince.